# Faizan Qazi

Email: faizanqazimoi@gmail.com Mb: +91 958-264-8335







# **EDUCATION:**

## **Bachelor of Technology**

Jammu University, 2007-2011

# **SKILLS:**

#### **Functional:**

Business Development, Sales, Pre-Sales ISO Standards, COBIT, NIST SP, OWASP, ITGC, ITAC, SOC1, SOC2, SSAE 16 / SAS 70

#### Technical:

Programming: Python, Java, SQL, PLSQL, Linux, Oracle reports, XML reports, Interface/Conversion, SAST, DAST

Platforms: Kali Linux, Oracle ERP, Oracle GRC, Archer GRC, Mobiquity Application

Tools: Nessus, Qualys, BurpSuite, NMAP, SonarQube, Metasploit, Archer GRC, Splunk, BluSapphire, TOAD, SQL Navigator, PL/SQL & SQL Plus developer

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT:

- CISSP (Oct 2022)
- ISC2 Cyber Security (Oct 2022)
- Certified information security manager
   CISM (June 2020)
- Oracle EBS R12 SCM Implementation Specialist – Purchasing Essentials (Sep 2013)
- Oracle EBS R12 SCM Implementation Specialist – Inventory Essentials (Oct 2013)
- ALIGN Ledership development program (2014-2015)
- Oracle Fusion-General Ledger (Nov 2013)
- Oracle Procurement Cloud Certified Implementation Specialist (Nov 2017)





# **PUBLICATIONS:**

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Information Security advisor with 13+ years of experience across Cyber Security Solutioning, Information Security and GRC. Expertise in IT Audit, ISO 27001,27701,22301, NIST-SP, Cloud Security Alliance, Privacy Assessment, PCI DSS, SAS 70 / SSAE 16, SOC1/SOC2, ITGC, ITAC, SOX compliance, Application Compliance Management, Risk Assessment, VA/PT, GDPR, etc.

I have subject matter expertise across sectors including FMCG, ITeS, Media, E-governance, IT Product, Banking, Telecom for Government & Private sector clients, solutioning their security governance and management, risk management, access controls, application security controls, vendor risk management.

As a manager and a Leder I have a strong network for building **business development opportunities** and partnerships for all stakeholders in the ecosystem across the globe.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Program Manager, KPMG for UIDAI

May 2022 to Present

- Led and advised the client's leadership team on overall cybersecurity program by liaising with key
  central govt. agencies and collaborating ministries such as MEITY, other agencies such as
  NCIIPC, NeGD, NIC and state level organizations.
- Designed audit frameworks, privacy policies, and information security policies for implementation across UIDAI ecosystem, their partner users of services and integrations
- Designed and managed implementation of information security, incident management and Business continuity management systems as per ISO 27001 and ISO 22301
- Led Governance Strategy and Vulnerability cyber-attack mitigation of the client's technology and
- Capacity building and cyber awareness advisory to all stakeholders and state government officials on effective implementation of Aadhar based solutions
- Orchestrated the strategic expansion of the security business unit, driving double-digit revenue growth year-over-year through targeted market penetration and innovative client engagement strategies
- Formulated and executed a comprehensive business development strategy that resulted in a
   150% increase in market share within the competitive security technology landscape
- Directed a high-performance team of business development professionals, fostering a culture excellence and achieving record-breaking sales milestones in the security sector.
- Directed the successful delivery of complex security projects and programs for global clients, consistently achieving project milestones on time and within budget, resulting in a 100% increase in client satisfaction scores

Lead, Information Security, IQVIA for National Health Authority (NHA)

2021 to 2022

- Led security design and implementation of India's flagship e-governance initiative by central
  government for building Cyber Security & Data Privacy frameworks, policies, guidelines, SOPs
  and systems for ABDM and PMJAY for National Health Authority (NHA)
- Led Solution Architecture development as a subject matter expert, collaborating with internal and external stakeholders on security solutions such as SIEM, DLP, IDAM, PIM, WAF, Firewall, Anti-APT, DRM, NAC, Packet Capture Solution, SOC, GRC, etc.
- Designed and implemented cloud security solutions, including cloud infrastructure and information security (ISMS and Health controls), Incident management, and Business continuity management system as per ISO 27001 and ISO 22301 covering all functions, office locations, data centers etc.

Addressing Efficiency and Security
<a href="Issues Through Oracle Project Status">Issues Through Oracle Project Status</a>
<a href="Inquiry">Inquiry</a> (PSI) Automation

# **INTERESTS:**

 Quantum Cryptography, Hashing Algorithms, Encryption

- Institutionalized Privacy & IS policies of digital health ID program of India including establishment of Security Operation Center (SOC)
- Provided advisory on vulnerability identification and mitigation through proactive fixes, patches, and assessments such as Web Application Security Assessment (WASA), API security, and Mobile Application Security Assessment (MASA)
- Led RFP solution designing, scoping and qualification requirements for cloud security solutions
- Conducted Web application security assessment and prioritized fixing vulnerabilities
- Managed and mentored internal, cross stakeholder team members, consultants and security analysts

# Deputy General Manager, Bharti Airtel

2020 to 2021

- Spearheaded development, budget management and implementation of risk management initiatives and business continuity management system as per ISO 27001 and ISO 22301
- Designed and managed implementation of information security policies, standards, procedures, guidelines, incident management systems and covering business functions, IT applications & products, office locations, data centers, telecom network sites and warehouses
- Managed Web Application Security Assessment (WASA), API security, Mobile Application Security
  Assessment (MASA), and other pre Go-Live procedures
- Managed programs and tracking adoption of best practices for information security awareness among top management, employees, contractors, and other stakeholders and

# Senior Manager (GRC & Security Advisory) Bharti Airtel

2018 to 2020

- Led governance, risk and compliance (GRC) transformation projects, security domains, tools and technology with team size of more than 13 people
- Led deployment of IT governance frameworks and best practices, including ITIL, COBIT, and ISO
   27001 and assessment of controls and processes for financial reporting, data security, availability, processing integrity, confidentiality, and privacy.
- Led design and implementation of IT general controls (ITGC) and ITAC controls to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of data.
- Led operations as the SME for conducting risk assessments, vulnerability assessments, and
  penetration testing to identify and mitigate potential security risks per gap analyses and provided
  recommendations for control enhancements and process improvements.
- Led design and development of audit frameworks, audit documentation, and coordination of audit
  activities including methodologies, such as COSO and COBIT for internal and external audit
  observations and responses as per the mitigating controls built in the applications
- Performed testing of IT general and operational controls audit for Sarbanes-Oxley and SAS70 compliance
- Evaluated IT control, analyzing and assessing IT controls, risk mitigation, security, compliance, including the entire IT audit process

# Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

2017 to 2018

- Developed, implemented and monitored Strategic & Comprehensive IS program ensuring Integrity,
   Confidentiality & Availability of information owned & controlled by client organizations
- Reviewed business continuity plans to determine the business strategy, the risks and the impact of unexpected disruptions for clients
- Reviewed and conducted testing for segregation of duties (SOD) and accessing control in application
- to ensure compliance with SOX.
- Managed Implementation and assessment of security and business process control in the application including segregation of duties, structural authorizations, access restrictions, role and profile assignments
- Conducted testing for application controls, including both logical and physical access, controls to
  ensure the effectiveness of functionality, good reporting, and interfaces.
- Conducted SOC1 assessments and audits to evaluate the design and operating effectiveness of internal controls over financial reporting
- Assisted in the development and implementation of control frameworks and processes in compliance with SSAE 18 (Statement on Standards for Attestation Engagements No. 18) requirements.

- Conducted walkthroughs and testing of financial controls to ensure compliance with regulatory requirements, such as SOX (Sarbanes-Oxley Act).
- Prepared and delivered SOC2 reports, including the Service Organization Control (SOC) 2 Type I
   and Type II reports, for distribution to clients and stakeholders.
- Worked closely with external auditors to facilitate SOC1 engagements and address audit findings.
- Worked on implementation of ISO 22301 (business continuity management system) including scope, design, implementation, testing of BCP/DRP, BIA (business impact analysis) and reporting to the management.

#### Senior (GRC Advisory), KPMG

2015 to 2017

- Managed the end-to-end delivery of multiple security projects, including management of project scoping, timelines, risks, budget, resourcing, deliverables, quality, and overall client satisfaction.
- Managed deliverable development, oversight, and presentation of various security project deliverables (e.g. security maturity assessments, risk assessments, Security controls readiness assessments and remediation support, security policies/procedures) and effectively present deliverables/findings to
- senior clients and stakeholders.
- Led governance, risk and compliance (GRC) transformation projects crossing industries, security
  domains, tools and technology with team size of 5 members
- Led SOC2 readiness assessments, evaluating security, availability, processing integrity, confidentiality, and privacy controls.
- Developed and implemented control frameworks aligned with Trust Services Criteria (TSC) and AICPA guidelines.
- Conducted risk assessments and vulnerability scans, identifying areas for improvement.
- Enhanced security by implementing proactive measures based on assessment findings.
- Prepared and presented concise SOC2 reports, highlighting compliance and control effectiveness.
- Conducted IT and business process audits for the management for ensuring business risks were recognized and appropriately managed before the company was adversely affected.
- Conducted reassessment of controls and deficiencies and retesting all the identified key controls within SOX guidelines.
- Performed ERP (Oracle) audits and conducting pre and post Oracle implementation reviews.
- Managed assessment of IT control elements to mitigate IT risks regarding the confidentiality, integrity, and the availability of business information.
- Reviewed the systems for IT general controls, risk and compliance with policies and regulations.
- Conducted identification and evaluation of risks during review and analysis of system development life cycle (SDLC), including Design, Testing/QA, and Implementation of systems and upgrades.
- Designed and implemented security structure in oracle application for the client around the globe
- Designed and implemented security controls frameworks and risk methodologies using Oracle AACG,
   CCG, PCG and TCG modules
- Designed the application security structure in Oracle R12/Oracle cloud for the clients across various business tracks (PTP, OTC, RTR etc.), adhering to client requirements
- Built Models and Controls in AACG for SoD Analysis and performed extensive false-positive analysis.
- Designed and configured snapshots and change tracker in CCG (configuration control governor) to monitor various configurations in Oracle e-Business Suite
- Executed subject matter expertise in ERP (Oracle) business processes and testing of relevant controls.

# Application Developer, Fujitsu Consulting

2011 to 2014

- Designed and developed interfaces, conversion, Oracle Reports, SQL and PLSQL reports on Oracle ERP platform
- Worked on Oracle modules -Project Accounting, Oracle Purchasing, Oracle Order Management,
   Oracle Time and Labour with insights on Procure to Pay and Order to Cash Cycles.
- Worked closely with application development teams to assess the security posture of applications.
- Worked with global development teams to build testing solutions and troubleshoot security issues in order to deliver product in high quality

• W • Pe	rerformed on-going security testing and code review to improve software security.  Worked on Oracle implementation, enhancement projects across industries.  Performance tuning of objects (SQL and PLSQL) using indexes and trees  Reveloped Oracle PL/SQL stored procedures, Functions, Packages, Triggers, Object Types, Views,  QL scripts to facilitate the functionality for various modules